### Nave G

nave.gill@outlook.com (905) 782-2350

# https://www.github.com/Navd15 https://www.linkedin.com/in/nave-gil

Machine Learning Engineer & Backend Developer

## **Summary**

Transiting to Data Science, Machine Learning & data engineering roles 4+ years of experience in backend development and 2+ year of experience in machine learning Expert in conceptualizing and developing robust backend systems for data-oriented problems

## Skills and technologies

python, pytorch, tensorflow, transformers, spacy, pandas, numpy, flask, gitlab, CI/CD, AWS (sagemaker, EC2, SQS, SNS, DynmoDB, lambda, ECR), postgreSQL, mongodb, nltk, regex, docker, django, boto3, node js, html, css, javascript

## **Experience**

Biztech2Go Inc. Mississauga, Ontario March 2022 - Present

Machine Learning Engineer | Backend Developer

- researching and evaluating state-of-the-art tranformer models for improved accuracy
- implementing the research papers and preparing proof of the concept in google colab
- collabrating with data science, business team and domain experts for model testing, decide metrics etc.
- developed dataset pipeline for pytorch and preprocessing
- trained spacy for developing the rule-based pipeline for documentation annotation
- developed AWS Sagemaker script mode for training and inference
- developed custom server pipeline for sagemaker in docker configuration
- developed CI/CD pipeline to automate deployment over ec2

HIE HQ Remote, India

Mid Senior Developer – Backend Developer

- Lead projects in Django and Node js
- Improved accuracy of the NLP model from 78% to 88% using tf-idf & boosting
- Wrote Gitlab CI/CD pipeline for new & existing projects
- Used web sockets for real time data transfer
- coached juniors and new joiners for version control systems- git, gitlab, github

**Zillion Analytics** Gurgaon, India Data Analytics Intern January 2019 - May 2019

Used Python to analyse real estate data for an international client

- Transformed data from excel to sql database
- Created visualizations using python & tableau

### **International Technology Solutions**

Junior Backend Developer

Remote, India

Nov 2019 - Dec 2021

June 2018 - October 2019

- Did statistical testing on medical data for anomalies using Python & MySQL
- Worked on REST API's using Node is & MongoDB
- Developed Single Page applications Native JavaScript & React is

### **Education**

**Lambton College** Toronto, Canada

**Graduate Certificate** 

Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning **Guru Nanak Dev University**B. Tech

Computer Science and Engineering

May 2021 – Jan 2023 Amritsar, India Sept 2014 – June 2018